Guide to the Witness to Guantanamo Video Collection, 2009-2017 RL.11691
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Interviews, 2009-2017; 10,000 Gigabytes secure server
  - Hénin, Nicolas, 2010-09-26; 1:45:20
    - Hénin, Nicolas - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file NicolasHénin.mov)
  - Hicks, Bev, 2012-01-02; 0:45:25
    Bev Hicks, female, age 69, the stepmother of former Guantanamo Bay detainee David Hicks, worked tirelessly for years with David's attorneys, and on February 19, 2015, got his conviction vacated.
    - Hicks, Bev - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file BevHicks.mov)
    - Hicks, Bev - short clip - MessagesofLove (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file BevHicks_MessagesofLove.mp4)
    - Hicks, Bev - short clip - NotTheSame (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file BevHicks_NotTheSame.mp4)
    - Hicks, Bev - short clip - NotTheSame (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file BevHicks_NotTheSame.mp4)
    - Hicks, Bev - short clip - VisitingDavid (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file BevHicks_VisitingDavid.mp4)
  - Hicks,Terry, 2012-01-02; 1:23:22
    Terry Hicks, male, age 66, is the father of Australian former Guantanamo Bay detainee David Hicks. He worked tirelessly for years with David's attorneys, and on February 19, 2015, got his conviction vacated.
    - Hicks,Terry - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file TerryHicks.mov)
    - Hicks,Terry - short clip - TheShockofSeeingDavid (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file TerryHicks_TheShockofSeeingDavid.mp4)
  - Holdbrooks, Terry, 2010-05-01; 1:47:17
    Terry Holdbrooks, male, age 26, served as a prison guard at Guantanamo from June 2003 until July 2004, converting to Islam during this time.
    - Holdbrooks, Terry - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file TerryHoldbrooks.mov)
    - Holdbrooks, Terry - short clip - PrisonerAbuse (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file TerryHoldbrooks_PrisonerAbuse.mp4)
    - Holdbrooks, Terry - short clip - RepatriatingPrisoners (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file TerryHoldbrooks_RepatriatingPrisoners.mp4)
    - Holdbrooks, Terry - short clip - Suicides (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file TerryHoldbrooks_Suicides.mp4)
    - Holdbrooks, Terry - short clip - Suicides (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file TerryHoldbrooks_Suicides_long.mp4)
    - Holdbrooks, Terry - short clip - TrainingforGuards (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file TerryHoldbrooks_TrainingforGuards.mp4)
  - Hosani, Nageeb Al, 2012-07-13; 0:26:41
    Nageeb Al Hosani, male, age 33, Moroccan, was detained in Guantanamo from February 7, 2002 until February 7, 2006, when he was returned to Morocco.
    - Hosani, Nageeb Al - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file NageebAlHosani.mov)
  - Husky, Kristine, 2010-08-09; 1:53:12
    Kristine Husky, female, age 42, has represented over fifteen Guantanamo detainees since 2002, including Omar Khadr, the young Canadian citizen charged with war crimes, in Rasul v. Bush in 2004.
    - Husky, Kristine - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file KristineHusky.mov)
    - Husky, Kristine - short clip - GuantanamoDoctors (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file KristineHusky_GuantanamoDoctors.mp4)
  - Iacopino, Vincent, 2017-09-25; 1:38:36
    Vincent Iacopino, male, age 60, is the senior medical advisor to Physicians for Human Rights, and the principle organizer behind the U.N. Istanbul Protocol, which provides guidelines on effective torture investigation and documentation. He has also testified in a number of Guantanamo detainee hearings.
    - Iacopino, Vincent - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file VincentIacopino.mov)
    - Iacopino, Vincent - short clip - BiggestMedicalEthicsScandalinUSHistory (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file VincentIacopino_BiggestMedicalEthicsScandalinUSHistory.mp4)
    - Iacopino, Vincent - short clip - MedicalStaffComplicityinTorture (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file VincentIacopino_MedicalStaffComplicityinTorture.mp4)
    - Iacopino, Vincent - short clip - TheWorstKindsofTorture (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file VincentIacopino_TheWorstKindsofTorture.mp4)
  - Idir, Mustafa Ait, 2009-08-07; 1:34:31
    Mustafa Ait Idir, male, age 39, a citizen of Algeria and Bosnia and Herzegovina, was detained in Guantanamo from January 20, 2002 until December 16, 2008 when he was released to Bosnia and Herzegovina after a federal judge ruled that he was not being lawfully held.
    - Idir, Mustafa Ait - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file MustafaAitIdir.mov)
    - Idir, Mustafa Ait - short clip - erf (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Moustafa_erf.mp4)
  - Jalaldin, Jalil, 2010-05-30; 2:10:45
    Jalil Jalaldin, male, age 30, a Uyghur from the Xinjiang autonomous region, was detained in Guantanamo from June 12, 2002 until June 11, 2009, when he was released to Bermuda. He won his habeas corpus suit in 2008, but was not released until the following year.
    - Jalaldin, Jalil - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file JalilJalaldin.mov)
  - Janko, Abdul Rahim, 2014-06-18; 2:24:24
    Interview may be accessed only via typescript in the Rubenstein Library reading room.
    Abdul Rahim Janko, male, age 35, Syrian-Kurd, was detained in Guantanamo from May 1, 2002 until Oct. 9, 2009, when he was released to Belgium.
    - Janko, Abdul Rahim - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file AbdulRahimJanko.mov)
    - Janko, Abdul Rahim - short clip - NotaBadPerson (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AbdulRahimJanko_NotaBadPerson.mp4)
  - Kadidal, Shayana, 2016-10-02; 1:22:40
    Shayana Kadidal, male, age 48, is a Senior Managing Attorney at the Center for Constitutional Rights, and has worked on the Guantanamo Global Justice Initiative, coordinating legal representation for Guantanamo detainees.
    - Kadidal, Shayana - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file ShayanaKadidal.mov)
  - Kamel, Abdullah Kamel Abudallah, 2011-01-02; 1:00:42
    Abdullah Kamel Abdullah Kamel, male, age 37, Kuwaiti, was detained in Guantanamo from February 11, 2002 until September 14, 2006, when he was repatriated to Kuwait.
    - Kamel, Abdullah Kamel Abudallah - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file AbdullahKamelAbdullahKamel.mov)
  - Kanouni, Imad, 2009-08-11; 2:22:52
    Imad Kanouni, male, age 32, French, was detained in Guantanamo from 2002 until July 26, 2004, when he was returned to France. In April 2006, he was acquitted by a French court.
    - Kanouni, Imad - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file ImadKanouni.mov)
    - Kanouni, Imad - short clip - Distractions (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file ImadKanouni_Distractions.mp4)
    - Kanouni, Imad - short clip - Injustice (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file ImadKanouni_Injustice.mp4)
    - Kanouni, Imad - short clip - MedicalCare (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file ImadKanouni_MedicalCare.mp4)
    - Kebriaei, Pardiss - short clip - AfterReleasetheUSWashesItsHands (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Pardiss Kebriaei_AfterReleasetheUSWashesItsHands.mp4)
    - Kebriaei, Pardiss - short clip - FatherandSonKeptApart (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Pardiss Kebriaei_FatherandSonKeptApart.mp4)
    - Kebriaei, Pardiss - short clip - TheOnesThatRemain (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file PardissKebriaei_TheOnesThatRemain.mp4)
  - Kenny, Stephen, 2012-01-01; 1:50:33
    Stephen Kenny, male, age 57, represented David Hicks and Mamdouh Habib, two Australians detained in Guantanamo.
    - Kenny, Stephen - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file StephenKenny.mov)
    - Kenny, Stephen - short clip - ConditionsforGoingtoGuantanamo (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file StephenKenny_ConditionsforGoingtoGuantanamo.mp4)
    - Kenny, Stephen - short clip - FallofAmericanDemocracy (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file StephenKenny_FallofAmericanDemocracy.mp4)
    - Kenny, Stephen - short clip - FallofAmericanDemocracy (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file StephenKenny_FallofAmericanDemocracy.mp4)
    - Kenny, Stephen - short clip - TheGuantanamoBayStandard (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file StephenKenny_TheGuantanamoBayStandard.mp4)
  - Khadr, Abdurahman, 2013-07-16; 1:57:49
    Abdurahman Khadr, male, age 30, a Canadian national of Egyptian origin, was detained in Guantanamo from March 23, 2003 until November 18, 2003, when he was released to Bosnia and Herzegovina.
    - Khadr, Abdurahman - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file AbdurahmanKhadr.mov)
    - Khadr, Abdurahman - short clip - ADayinEachOthersShoes (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AbdurahmanKhadr_ADayinEachOthersShoes.mp4)
    - Khadr, Abdurahman - short clip - TrainingCampat12YearsOld (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AbdurahmanKhadr_TrainingCampat12YearsOld.mp4)
  - Kurnaz, Murat, 2009-08-19; 2:13:42
    Murat Kurnaz, male 27, age, Turkish citizen and legal resident of Germany, was detained in Guantanamo from February 13, 2002 until August 24, 2006, when he was released to Germany.
    - Kurnaz, Murat - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file MuratKurnaz.mov)
    - Kurnaz, Murat - short clip - Hanging (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Murat_Hanging.mp4)
    - Kurnaz, Murat - short clip - Hanging (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Murat_Hanging_short.mp4)
    - Kurnaz, Murat - short clip - Hangingnew (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Murat_Hangingnew.mp4)
    - Kurnaz, Murat - short clip - NoRules (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Murat_NoRules.mp4)
    - Kurnaz, Murat - short clip - NoRules (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MuratKurnaz_NoRules.mp4)
  - Laalami, Mohammed Souleimani, 2012-07-13; 1:31:22
    Mohammed Souleimani Laalami, male, age 36, was detained in Guantanamo from February 2, 2002 until February 7, 2006, when he was released to Morocco. Upon his return to Morocco, Laalami was convicted of "forming a criminal group" and sentenced to five years, however he won his appeal in May 2007 and was acquitted. In 2013, he was killed while fighting in Syria.
    - Laalami, Mohammed Souleimani - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file MohammedSouleimaniLaalamiShadowed.mov)
  - Lahmar, Saber, 2010-08-05; 2:46:28
    Saber Lahmar, male, age 41, Algerian, was detained in Guantanamo from January 20, 2002 until November 30, 2009, when he won his Habeas Corpus petition and was released to France.
    - Lahmar, Saber - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file SaberLahmar.mov)
    - Lahmar, Saber - short clip - NottheSheraton (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file SaberLahmar_NottheSheraton.mp4)
    - Lahmar, Saber - short clip - OrdersFromAbove (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file SaberLahmar_OrdersFromAbove.mp4)
    - Lahmar, Saber - short clip - ThisIsYourLifeNow (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file SaberLahmar_ThisIsYourLifeNow.mp4)
  - Lakemacher, Daniel, 2010-10-30; 2:45:45
    Daniel Lakemacher, male, age 27, was a Hospital Corpsman deployed to Guantanamo for six months in 2008. He was granted discharge on September 11, 2009 as a conscientious objector.
    - Lakemacher, Daniel - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file DanielLakemacher.mov)
    - Lakemacher, Daniel - short clip - ComingtoTermsWithWhatIDid (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file DanielLakemacher_ComingtoTermsWithWhatIDid.mp4)
    - Lakemacher, Daniel - short clip - IronyBehindTheWire (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file DanielLakemacher_IronyBehindTheWire.mp4)
    - Lakemacher, Daniel - short clip - TheDehumanizationofForcedFeedings (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file DanielLakemacher_TheDehumanizationofForcedFeedings.mp4)
  - Lehnert, Michael, 2011-08-09; 2:04:48
    Michael Lehnert, male, age 60, was the first commander of the Guantanamo Bay detention facility from December 21, 2001 until March 28, 2002. In May 2015, General Lehnert authored a letter in support of closing Guantanamo Bay.
    - Lehnert, Michael - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file MichaelLehnert.mov)
    - Lehnert, Michael - short clip - AllowingAnonymityforSoldiersWasaMistake (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MichaelLehnert_AllowingAnonymityforSoldiersWasaMistake.mp4)
    - Lehnert, Michael - short clip - GuantanamosLessonsShouldGuideUsNextTime (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MichaelLehnert_GuantanamosLessonsShouldGuideUsNextTime.mp4)
    - Lehnert, Michael - short clip - SeparatingtheSheepfromtheGoats (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MichaelLehnert_SeparatingtheSheepfromtheGoats.mp4)
  - Lewis, Paul, 2017-05-31; 1:29:40
    Paul Lewis, male, age 58, was the Department of Defense Special Envoy for Guantanamo Closure from October 2013 until February 2, 2017, and during his tenure was able to reduce the number of detainees remaining at the prison to 41.
    - Lewis, Paul - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file PaulLewis.mov)
    - Lewis, Paul - short clip - HurtingMoreThanHelping (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file PaulLewis_HurtingMoreThanHelping.mp4)
    - Lewis, Paul - short clip - TransferNotRelease (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file PaulLewis_TransferNotRelease.mp4)
  - Lietzau, William, 2013-11-22; 2:52:23
    William Lietzau, male, age 53, was Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Detainee Policy, and Deputy Legal Adviser to the National Security Council, and led the United States negotiating team responsible for defining war crimes for the International Criminal Court.
    - Lietzau, William - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file WilliamLietzau.mov)
    - Lietzau, William - short clip - AreDroneStrikesLegal (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file WilliamLietzau_AreDroneStrikesLegal.mp4)
    - Lietzau, William - short clip - ConstantlyinaLittleBitofWar (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file WilliamLietzau_ConstantlyinaLittleBitofWar.mp4)
    - Lietzau, William - short clip - WeNeedAnEndgame (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file WilliamLietzau_WeNeedAnEndgame.mp4)
  - Lindh, Frank, 2011-04-02; 2:02:09
    Frank Lindh, male, age 58, is the father of John Walker Lindh, a 20 year-old American citizen captured in Afghanistan in November 2001 and held for 54 days without access to family or lawyers.
    - Lindh, Frank - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file FrankLindh.mov)
    - Lindh, Frank - short clip - LetterNeverDelivered (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file FrankLindh_LetterNeverDelivered.mp4)
    - Lindh, Frank - short clip - NotaRippleofObjection (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file FrankLindh_NotaRippleofObjection.mp4)
    - Lindh, Frank - short clip - TaketheGlovesOff (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file FrankLindh_TaketheGlovesOff.mp4)
    - Lindh, Frank - short clip - WhyWasJohnThere (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file FrankLindh_WhyWasJohnThere.mp4)
    - Lindh, Frank - short clip - WhyWasJohnThere (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file FrankLindh_WhyWasJohnThere.mp4)
  - Liotta, Alan, 2017-07-20; 1:47:38
    Alan Liotta, male, age 58, was appointed Principal Director of the Office of Detainee Policy in the Department of Defense in 2006 and was responsible for negotiating the transfers of more than 380 Guantanamo detainees.
    - Liotta, Alan - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file AlanLiotta.mov)
    - Liotta, Alan - short clip - MovingtheProblemNorth (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AlanLiotta-MovingtheProblemNorth.mp4)
    - Liotta, Alan - short clip - NoWartimeDetentionMeansWarCrimesandDeath (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AlanLiotta_NoWartimeDetentionMeansWarCrimesandDeath.mp4)
  - Mahnut, Bahtiyar, 2010-09-26; 2:14:32
    Bahtiyar Mahnut, male, age 34, a Uyghur from the Xinjiang autonomous region, was detained in Guantanamo from June 2002 until March 22, 2010, when he was released to Switzerland. In October 2008, he won his habeas corpus suit, however he was not released until both himself and his brother were granted political asylum in 2010.
    - Mahnut, Bahtiyar - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file BahtiyarMahnut.mov)
  - Mallow, Brittain, 2014-11-14; 2:02:46
    Brittain Mallow, male, age 58, was Commander of the Criminal Investigation Task Force (CITF) (2002-2005), and ordered the task force to discontinue the increasingly coercive interrogation tactics being used at the Guantanamo Bay detention center.
    - Mallow, Brittain - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file BrittainMallow.mov)
    - Mallow, Brittain - short clip - CultureofExperimentation (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file BrittainMallow_CultureofExperimentation.mp4)
    - Mallow, Brittain - short clip - ExpectingAnotherAttack (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file BrittainMallow_ExpectingAnotherAttack.mp4)
    - Mallow, Brittain - short clip - UpsideDownInvestigation (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file BrittainMallow_UpsideDownInvestigation.mp4)
  - Mamut, Khalil, 2010-05-30; 2:08:53
    Khalil Mamut, male, age 32 or 33, a Uyghur from the Xinjiang autonomous region, was detained in Guantanamo from October 6, 2002 until June 11, 2009, when he was released to Bermuda.
    - Mamut, Khalil - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file KhalilMamut.mov)
    - Mamut, Khalil - short clip - DentistVisit (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file KhalilMamut_DentistVisit.mp4)
    - Mamut, Khalil - short clip - DeprivedofFamily (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file KhalilMamut_DeprivedofFamily.mp4)
    - Mamut, Khalil - short clip - ShootMe (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file KhalilMamut_ShootMe.mp4)
    - Mamut, Khalil - short clip - Suicides (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file KhalilMamut_Suicides.mp4)
  - Marfadi, Hussein Al-, interview 1, 2015-02-22; 2:11:18
    Prior to viewing the interview, permission must be obtained from either David Remes, Al-marfadi's lawyer (remesdh@gmail.com), or Ashraf Michael, his interpreter (ashrafmichael@gmail.com). Interview may be accessed only via the electronic records and media computer in the Rubenstein Library reading room.
    Hussein Al-marfadi, male, age 37, Yemeni, was detained in Guantanamo from May 9, 2003 until November 20, 2014, when he was released to Slovakia.
    - Marfadi, Hussein Al-, interview 1 - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file HusseinAl-marfadi_Part1.mov)
  - Marfadi, Hussein Al-, interview 2, 2015-02-23; 4:01:55
    - Marfadi, Hussein Al-, interview 2 - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file HusseinAl-marfadi_Part2.mov)
  - Margulies, Joseph, 2012-02-16; 1:46:24
    Joseph Margulies, male, age 51, was Counsel of Record in Rasul v. Bush (2004), the case that established statutory habeas rights for Guantanamo detainees, and is counsel for Abu Zubaydah, a "high-value" detainee whose interrogation led to the infamous "torture memos." He also testified at the first Senate Judiciary Committee hearing on detainee issues in 2005.
    - Margulies, Joseph - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file JosephMargulies.mov)
    - Margulies, Joseph - short clip - APoliticalManeuver (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file JosephMargulies_APoliticalManeuver.mp4)
    - Margulies, Joseph - short clip - GainingaClient (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file JosephMargulies_GainingaClient.mp4)
    - Margulies, Joseph - short clip - WhatGuantanamoHasBecome (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file JosephMargulies_WhatGuantanamoHasBecome.mp4)
  - Mcfadden, Robert, 2014-08-19; 1:59:16
    Robert Mcfadden, male, age 56, worked at the Naval Criminal Investigative Service from 2008-2011, serving as Deputy Assistant Director of Counterintelligence Operations for his final year.
    - Mcfadden, Robert - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file RobertMcfadden.mov)
    - Mcfadden, Robert - short clip - HarassmentNotInterrogation (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file RobertMcFadden_HarassmentNotInterrogation.mp4)
    - Mcfadden, Robert - short clip - NoScienceSupportingHumiliation (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file RobertMcfadden_NoScienceSupportingHumiliation.mp4)
  - Meister, Ronald, 2016-05-25; 1:13:27
    Ronald Meister, male, age 69, has successfully represented since 2014 a Navy nurse at Guantanamo Bay who refused to carry out orders to force-feed detainee hunger-strikers.
    - Meister, Ronald - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file RonaldMeister.mov)
    - Meister, Ronald - short clip - DerelictionofDuty (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file RonMeister_DerelictionofDuty.mp4)
  - Mendez, Juan, 2016-11-04; 1:25:19
    Juan Mendez, male, age 71, was UN Special Rapporteur on Torture and Other Cruel, Inhuman and Degrading Treatment or Punishment from November 2010 until October 2016.
    - Mendez, Juan - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file JuanMendez.mov)
    - Mendez, Juan - short clip - GuardsDontCount (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file JuanMendez_GuardsDontCount.mp4)
    - Mendez, Juan - short clip - SolitaryConfinementAsTorture (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file JuanMendez_SolitaryConfinementAsTorture.mp4)
    - Mendez, Juan - short clip - USIsFailingItsInternationalObligations (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file JuanMendez_USIsFailingItsInternationalObligations.mp4)
  - Mickum, George Brent, 2012-10-02; 2:25:50
    George Brent Mickum, male, age 58, is an attorney who represented Guantanamo detainees Bisher Al Rawi, Jamil El Banna, and Martin Mubanga, as well as Abu Zubaydah, one of the "high-value" detainees.
    - Mickum, George Brent - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file GeorgeBrentMickum.mov)
    - Mickum, George Brent - short clip - APoliticalBeing (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file GeorgeBrentMickum_APoliticalBeing.mp4)
    - Mickum, George Brent - short clip - SystematicallyTrimmingtheConstitution (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file GeorgeBrentMickum_SystematicallyTrimmingtheConstitution.mp4)
    - Mickum, George Brent - short clip - ThereIsNoLaw (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file GeorgeBrentMickum_ThereIsNoLaw.mp4)
    - Mickum, George Brent - short clip - ThereIsNoLaw (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file GeorgeBrentMickum_ThereIsNoLaw.mp4)
    - Mickum, George Brent - short clip - ThereIsNoLaw2 (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file GeorgeBrentMickum_ThereIsNoLaw2.mp4)
    - Mickum, George Brent - short clip - ThereIsNoLaw3 (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file GeorgeBrentMickum_ThereIsNoLaw3.mp4)
  - Mohamed, Ben Moujane, 2012-07-11; 1:31:11
    Ben Moujane Mohamed, male, age 31, Moroccan, was detained in Guantanamo from January 14, 2002 until October, 11 2006, when he was returned to Morocco.